#### Scott Clarke

Email: scott\_jc\_clarke@hotmail.com GitHub: /Scott-J-Clarke | LinkedIn: /scottjcclarke

Web developer and former teacher who worked in Taiwan for 13-plus years. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Texas. Problem-solver interested in listening to and learning from all colleagues. Strengths in daily execution and communication.

#### Technical Skills

MongoDB, Express, React, Node, GitHub, JavaScript, GraphQL, CSS, HTML, SQL

### **Projects**

Dose of Daily Tech | GitHub: https://github.com/Scott-J-Clarke/groovy-tech-blog-v2 Heroku: https://groovy-tech-blog-v2-9abbdd8362ed.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Blog where users read, write, and comment on coding concepts.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: Express, Node, JavaScript, Handlebars, SQL, doteny, bcrypt

Note Taker | GitHub: https://github.com/Scott-J-Clarke/note-taker-version-2 Heroku: https://note-taker-version-2-2379b1830cc5.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Application where users write, save, and review notes.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: Node, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

- Summary: Application takes user input and creates a custom logo for them.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: Node, JavaScript, HTML

## Experience

### Owner

Sept 2022 – Present

#### **Vivid Quill Resources**

Teachers Pay Teachers (TPT)

- Made 70+ teaching-related products, including lesson plans and handouts.
- Built International Baccalaureate (IB) resources to help teachers around the world better execute "the exhibition" process with their students.
- Created reading comprehension passages on a range of historical topics, including "Why Do We Study History?" and "The Impact of Agriculture."

#### 5th Grade Teacher

Aug 2016 – July 2022

### Taipei Kuei Shan School

Taipei, Taiwan

- Worked with 70+ people, including colleagues and administrators, to help guide students through semester-long research project called "the exhibition."
- Developed and taught multiple 6-week long units that integrated different subjects, IB pedagogy, and Common Core State Standards (CCSS).
- Was 5<sup>th</sup> Grade Level Head, responsible for communicating with co-teachers, crafting collaborative long-term plans, and running concise weekly meetings.

#### Middle School Teacher

Feb 2009 – June 2016

### Taipei Fuhsing Private School

Taipei, Taiwan

- Was Head of the English Department, responsible for integrating curriculum standards, organizing professional development, and mediating disputes.
- Taught a range of novels, plays, and poems as an English literature teacher.
- Collaborated with colleague to execute 8<sup>th</sup> Grade Ancient History course.
- Produced own syllabi for Drama and History of Basketball courses.

# **Adult Education Teacher**

Oct 2006 – Aug 2007

#### TriArch Educational Services

Cobourg, Canada

- Fostered a positive learning environment for adults who had lost their employment due to an on-the-job injury and were being retrained to work.
- Taught high school-level English, math, and accounting in 1-on-1 setting.

### Education

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development – University of Texas

Austin, Texas

Bachelor of Education - University of Ottawa

Ottawa, Canada

Bachelor of Arts, English and History – Queen's University

Kingston, Canada